Guide to the Jazz Loft Project Records, 1950-2012 and undated RL.10001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral Histories, 1991-2010; 614 items
  - Pierce, Bill, 2004 September 14; Archival Resource Key; 72
    Bill Pierce (b 1935) was born in Waterbury, CT. A photographer with a background in theater, he was a longtime friend and associate of Gene Smith. Pierce introduced Smith to future collaborator Carole Thomas, who also came from a theater background. Pierce named his son William Eugene after Smith.
    In this oral history, Pierce discusses his personal background and education, as well as his development as an artist. He also talks about working W. Eugene Smith and goes into specific detail about Smith's creative and technical processes.
    - Bill Pierce Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Bill Pierce, 9/14/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0095)
    - Bill Pierce, 9/14/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0096)
    - Bill Pierce, 9/14/04, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0097)
    - Bill Pierce, 9/14/04, IV, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0098)
    - Bill Pierce, 9-14-04, 1/3, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0092)
    - Bill Pierce, 9-14-04, [2] of 3, Jumps to Pierce-end @ 59:25, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0093)
    - Bill Pierce, 9-14-04, 3/3 tapes, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0094)
    - Ben Riley, 9-12-04, 1/2, Village Vanguard, Bill Pierce, 9-14 at very end, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0096)
    - Bill Pierce, 1/4, 9/14/04, Dan, Sam, Bill, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 September 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0094)
    - Bill Pierce, 2/4, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 September 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0095)
    - Bill Pierce, #3/4, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 September 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0096)
    - Bill Pierce, 4/4, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 September 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0097)
  - Redd, Freddie, 2003 June 20; Archival Resource Key; 73
    Freddie Redd, Jr., (b 1928) was born in New York City. A jazz pianist, Redd participated in many jam sessions in the loft in the late 1950s and early 1960s. He was the composer and pianist for Jack Gelber's 1959 play, The Connection, which opened at the Living Theater on 14th Street and Sixth Avenue. Redd remembers the opening night party being at the Jazz Loft.
    In this oral history, Redd talks about his musical background, his experiences as a member of the Army in World War II, and his involvement with the New York City jazz scene. Spending two years at the Jazz Loft building, Redd discusses gigs and jam sessions he participated in, as well as his interactions with musicians including Charlie Parker. Redd also talks about composing the soundtrack for "The Connection", a play which depicted the music and drug culture prevalent in the Village during the 1950's.
    - Freddie Redd, 6/20/03, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 20 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0099)
    - Freddy Redd, 6/20/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 20 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0095)
    - Freddie Redd, 6/20/03, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0036)
    - Freddie Redd, 6/20/03, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2003 June 20 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0037)
    - Freddie Redd w/Sam Stephenson; Los Angeles, Audio-cassette, undated (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0141)
  - Reich, Steve, 2007 December 5; Archival Resource Key; 96
    Steve Reich (b 1936) is a world-renowned composer who studied with Hall Overton, Vincent Persichetti, and Luciano Berio among others. He attended Cornell University, the Juilliard School, and Mills College. Reich is most notably recognized for his work in the field of minimal music.
    In this oral history, Reich discusses his musical education at Cornell and later, with Hall Overton and Vincent Persichetti. Reich goes into detail about Overton's teaching style and philosophy, the value of what he learned in lessons, and what it was like to visit the Jazz Loft.
    - Steve Reich 12.05.07, Compact disc, 2007 December 5; 66 minutes (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0229)
  - Reilly, Jack, 2007 January 13; Archival Resource Key; 74
    Jack Reilly (b. 1932) was born on Staten Island, New York. He studied piano at Manhattan School of Music, and later he studied jazz piano and composition under Hall Overton, becoming his longtime friend and associate.
    In this oral history, Reilly talks about his musical education including studying with Lennie Tristano, attending the Manhattan School of Music, and taking lessons from Hall Overton at the Jazz Loft. Reilly also goes into detail about his work as an educator on Staten Island and his memories of playing gigs in New York City.
    - Jack Reilly Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Jack Reilly, 1/13/07, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2007 January 13; 63 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0100)
    - Jack Reilly, 1/13/07, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2007 January 13; 56 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0101)
  - Riley, Ben, 2004 September 12; Archival Resource Key; 75
    Ben Riley (b 1933) was born in Savannah, GA. A drummer, Riley participated in Thelonious Monk's big band rehearsals in the loft in 1964.
    - Untitled, digital audio tape, 2004 September 12 (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0141)
    - Untitled, digital audio tape, 2004 September 12 (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0142)
    - Ben Riley, 9-12-04, 1/2, Village Vanguard, Bill Pierce, 9-14 at very end, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 12 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0096)
    - Ben Riley, 9-12-04, Tape # 2/2, Village Vanguard, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 12 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0097)
  - Robinson, Perry, 2004 August 11; Archival Resource Key; 76
    Perry Robinson (b 1938) was born in New York City. A composer and clarinet player, he participated in loft jam sessions circa 1963-64.
    - Jeremy Steig, Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0102)
    - Jeremy Steig, Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0103)
    - Jeremy Steig, 8-11-04, Perry Robinson, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0107)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, II, 8-11-04, at Steig's Apt., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0108)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 11 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0112)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 11 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0113)
  - Rosenberg, Sam, 2006 October 09; Archival Resource Key; 77
    Sam Rosenberg was the longtime family owner of Superior Florist, located across the street from the loft, and seen in many Smith photographs from his window.
    In this oral history, Rosenberg discusses the Flower District in New York City, with particular attention to the artistic and creative community that flourished there in the 1950's and 1960's. Rosenberg also talks about his family's history and his father's flower shop. Of particular note are Rosenberg's memories of W. Eugene Smith, whom he remembered seeing around the neighborhood.
    - Sam Rosenberg Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Sam Rosenberg, 10/9/06, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 09 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0104)
    - Sam Rosenberg, Flowers, 10-9-06, Dan Partridge, Sam Stephenson, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2006 October 09 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0098)
  - Rosenthal, Mel, 2004 October 07; Archival Resource Key; 78
    Mel Rosenthal (b. 1940) was born in South Bronx. He studied photography with Gene Smith in the loft and became a well known photographer, activist, and professor.
    - Mel Rosenthal, 1/1, 10-7-04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 October 07 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0099)
  - Rothman, David, 2006 October 10; Archival Resource Key; 79
    David Rothman was a framemaker in New York City, the son of artist and frame shop owner Henry Rothman, whose shop was half a block away from the loft on 28th Street. Rothman wandered into the loft at age 14 in the late 1950's and remembers seeing Art Farmer and Jimmy Guiffre there. Later on in life, he rekindled a friendship with David X. Young and was appointed executor of his estate.
    In this oral history, Rothman talks about his father's framing business, which was right around the corner from the Jazz Loft Building in New York City. Rothman's father met David X. Young and helped him become acquainted with the people who owned the Jazz Loft building. Rothman also talks about the history of the Flower District, the scene at the Jazz Loft, his own interest and experience with music, and his friendship later in life with Young.
    - David Rothman Transcripts, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - David Rothman, 10/10/06, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 10 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0105)
    - David Rothman, 10-10-06, Frameshop, 1/2, Sam S, Dan P., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2006 October 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0100)
    - David Rothman, 10-10-06, 2/2, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2006 October 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0101)
  - Russo, Charles, 2006 October 09; Archival Resource Key; 80
    Charles Russo (1926-2012) was born in Pittsburgh, PA. At the close of World War II, Russo met Hall Overton in Germany when both were assigned to the 32nd Armored Regiment Band. They reconnected in the late 1940s when Russo studied at the Manhattan School of Music and Hall at Juilliard. He took jazz lessons from Overton in the loft, in exchange for painting Overton's ceiling. Russo had a long and distinguished career, playing with numerous orchestras including his position as Principal Clarinet in the New York City Opera.
    In this oral history, Russo discusses his musical background, his educational experiences at Manhattan School of Music, and his friendship with Hall Overton that began during World War II. Russo also talks about the limitations placed on jazz musicians by other "professional" musicians and establishments.
    - Charles Russo Transcripts, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Charles Russo, 10/9/06, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 09 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0106)
    - Charles Russo, 10/9/06, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 09 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0107)
    - Charles Russo, 10/9/06, III, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2006 October 09 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0108)
    - Russo Interview, Stephenson, Partridge, 1/3, ~1 hr, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2006 October 09 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0038)
    - Russo interview, Stephenson, Partridge, NYC, 2/3, ~1 hr, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2006 October 09 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0039)
    - Charles Russo interview, 3/3, NYC, ~37 m, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2006 October 09 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0040)
  - Sibley, Dave and Deanne Sibley, 2005 October 17; Archival Resource Key; 82
    Dave Sibley (1934-2008) was born in Pineville, LA and died in Columbus, OH. A jazz bassist, he lived in the loft in the summer of 1961 and participated in many sessions that summer.
    In this oral history Dave Sibley and his wife Deanne discuss their experiences at the Jazz Loft, the story of their relationship, and the jazz scene in New York City. Specifically, the Sibleys talk about saxophonist Lin Halliday, the New York drug culture, and the racial/social issues amongst jazz musicians in the 1960's.
    - Dave and Deanne Sibley Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Dave & Deanne Sibley, I, 10/17/05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 October 17 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0109)
    - Dave Sibley, II, 10/17/05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 October 17 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0110)
    - Dave Sibley, 10-17-05, Columbus Ohio, Dan Partridge, Sam Stephenson, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 October 17 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0102)
    - Dave Sibley, 10-17-05, Columbus, Ohio, Dan P., Sam S., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 October 17 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0103)
    - Dave Sibley, 10-17-05, Columbus, Ohio, D.P., S.S., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 October 17 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0104)
    - Dave Sibley (3 of 3), Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2005 October 17 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0041)
    - Dave & Deanne Sibley, I, 10/17/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 October 17 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0098)
    - Dave Sibley, II, 10/17/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 October 17 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0099)
  - Simpkins, Dr. Cuthbert, 2008 March 19; 84
    Cuthbert O. Simpkins, Jr., MD (b. 1947) was born in Chicago, IL. While in medical school at Harvard, he wrote the first biography of jazz saxophonist and composer John Coltrane. He became a trauma surgeon, researcher, and activist.
    In this oral history, Simpkins talks about his upbringing in Louisiana, his early exposure to music, and his medical training and practice. Also of particular note is Simpkins' discussion about a John Coltrane biography he wrote.
    - Sam Stephenson & Tom Tyson, Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, 3/19/08, Pre-interview in car from airport, Shreveport, LA, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0042)
    - Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, 3/19/08, I, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0043)
    - Sam Stephenson & Tom Tyson, Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, I, 3/19/08, Shreveport, LA, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0044)
    - Sam Stephenson & Tom Tyson, Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, II, 3/19/08, Shreveport, LA, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0045)
    - Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, 3/19/08, II, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0046)
    - Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, 3/19/08, III, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0047)
    - Sam Stephenson & Tom Tyson, Dr. Cuthbert Simpkins, III, 3/19/08, Shreveport, LA, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 19 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0048)
  - Singleton, Alvin, undated; 85
    Alvin Singleton talks about growing up in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, amongst many jazz musicians. Singleton discusses studying with Hall Overton at the Jazz Loft, as well as his other educational experiences with composers including Charles Wuorinen, Roger Sessions, and Gunther Schuller.
    - Alvin Singleton Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Kevin and Maggie Smith, 2008 June 29; 87
    Maggie Smith was the wife of W. Eugene Smith and the mother of Kevin Eugene Smith.
    In this oral history, Maggie and Kevin Smith discuss their lives and relationship with W. Eugene Smith. Maggie talks about her own work as a photographer at great length. Great detail is given about Gene Smith's mentality, work ethic, creative process, and family dynamics. Also discussed are Smith's exhibitions and publications.
    - Maggie Smith & Kevin Smith, 6/29/08, I, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 June 29 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0049)
    - Maggie Smith & Kevin Smith, 6/29/2008, II, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 June 29 (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0050)
  - Smith, Patrick, Phyllis Smith, Shana Smith Rasmus, and Marissa Smith, 2005 May 10; Archival Resource Key; 90
    Patrick Smith is W. Eugene Smith's son, and one of the children depicted in Smith's most famous photograph, "The Walk to Paradise Garden". Phyllis Smith is Patrick Smith's wife and W. Eugene Smith's daughter-in-law.
    Marissa Smith is W. Eugene Smith's daughter, named after a flamenco dancer named Marissa Flores.
    Shana Smith Rasmus, born in Croton, NY, is W. Eugene Smith's daughter. She is documented in a memorable photograph of her standing on the railing of the stairwell inside the loft building.
    In this oral history, Smith family members--Pat, Shana, and Phyllis--talk about W. Eugene Smith's life in depth, particularly his relationships with his wives and children, his creativity and artistic output, and their memories of the Jazz Loft building. Of particular note is their discussion of Smith's drug addiction, family interactions and conflicts over the years, the Smith children's personal and professional development over the years. Other people mentioned include photographer Jim Karales, family friend Ivan Tentchoff, and Smith's wife Aileen M. Smith.
    In another interview Pat Smith and Ivan Tentchoff discuss the dynamics of the Smith household, their own friendship, and W. Eugene's Smith life and work. In particular, Pat talks about his father's creative process and borderline obsessive behavior when it came to making art. Ivan talks about befriending the family and looking out for Pat during Smith's frequent absences.
    - Ivan Tentchoff/Pat Smith Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Ivan Tentchoff, Pat Smith, 9/22/05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 September 22 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0114)
    - Pat Smith, Shana Rasmus, 5-10-05, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 May 10; 64 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0111)
    - Pat Smith, Shana Rasmus, 5-10-05, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 May 10; 45 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0112)
    - Pat & Phyllis Smith, w/Sister Marissa Rasmus, 5-10-05, Some w/no DAT, around house, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 May 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0105)
    - Pat & Phyllis Smith w/ Marissa Smith - Rasmus, 5/10/5, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 May 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0106)
    - Pat Smith & Shana Rasmus, 5-10-05, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 May 10 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0100)
    - Pat Smith & Shana Rasmus, 5-10-05, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 May 10 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0101)
    - Ivan Tentchoff & Pat Smith, 9/22/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 September 22 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0114)
  - Snead, Terrell, 2005 October 20; Archival Resource Key; 92
    Terrell Snead (b. 1941) is the daughter of the Smith family's beloved housekeeper, Jazmine Twyman, both of whom lived in the Smith home in Croton-on-Hudson with the family beginning around 1950.
    In this oral history, Snead discusses her relationship with W. Eugene Smith and his family. As a tenant of the Smith household, Snead became quite close with Smith's children and talks in great detail about the dynamics of the family.
    - Terrell Snead, 10/20/05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 October 20 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0113)
    - Terrell Snead, Pittsburgh, 10-20-05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 October 20 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0111)
  - Soybel, Arthur, 2007 July 18; Archival Resource Key; 93
    Arthur Soybel was an attorney who negotiated W. Eugene Smith's divorce from his wife Aileen in the mid-1970's.
    - Arthur Soybel, 7/18/07, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2007 July 18 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0115)
  - Steig, Jeremy, 2004 August 11; 94
    Jeremy Steig (b. 1942) is the son of artist William Steig. A jazz flautist, Jeremy participated in a number of jam sessions in the loft between 1963 and 1964, whith Chick Corea and others.
    - Jeremy Steig, Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0102)
    - Jeremy Steig, Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0103)
    - Jeremy Steig, 8-11-04, Perry Robinson, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0107)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, II, 8-11-04, at Steig's Apt., Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0108)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 11 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0112)
    - Jeremy Steig & Perry Robinson, 8/11/04, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 11 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0113)
  - Stephenson, Sam, 2004 August 11; 95
    Sam Stephenson is a writer--affiliated with the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University--whose research and documentation of W. Eugene Smith's life has yielded two books, "Dream Street" and "The Jazz Loft Project". Stephenson is also working on a comprehensive Smith biography.
    - 8-22-07, Lois Deloatch, Sam Stephenson, Aaron Greenwald, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0027)
    - Sam Stephenson, Talk I., 8-11-04, Bill Crow, Dick Katz, Center for Jewish History, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0109)
    - Stephenson Talk Cont'd (II), Plus Bill Crow & Dick Katz, at Center for Jewish History, 8-11-04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0110)
    - Sam Stephenson with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, 2004 August 11; 81
      - Sam Stephenson 8-11-2004 with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, Compact disc, 2004 August 11 (Box 35, Video-disc RL10001-CD-0227)
      - Sam Stephenson 8-11-2004 with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, Compact disc, 2004 August 11 (Box 35, Video-disc RL10001-CD-0228)
      - Sam Stephenson 8-11-2004 with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, Compact disc, 2004 August 11 (Box 30, Video-disc RL10001-CD-0259)
      - Sam Stephenson 8-11-2004 with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, Compact disc, 2004 August 11 (Box 30, Video-disc RL10001-CD-0260)
      - Sam Stephenson 8-11-2004 with Bill Crow and Dick Katz, Compact disc, 2004 August 11 (Box 30, Video-disc RL10001-CD-0261)
  - Stevenson, James, 2003 June 16; Archival Resource Key; 97
    James "Jimmy" Stevenson (1939-2010) was born in Detroit, MI. A bassist, he was a fifth floor loft resident from 1961-1964, during which time he hosted many great jam sessions. There were so many sessions with so many different musicians that Gene Smith took to simply writing "Jimmy Jam" on reels recorded in Stevenson's space.